<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <Name>Beef's SEGI Plus</Name>
    <Author>TheRealBeef</Author>
    <Version>1.2.4</Version>

    <Description>
        [h1]Beef's SEGI Plus[/h1]
        [b]WARNING:[/b] This is a StationeersLaunchPad Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed with the StationeersLaunchPad plugin.
        See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

        There is an in-game config menu with F11.

        A modified version of SEGI (Sonic Ether Global Illumination) for Stationeers with shader fixes and performance options.

        - 4 quality presets (Low/Medium/High/Extreme)
        - Lightweight Mode that voxelizes only emissive objects for maximum performance at the cost of more light leakage
        > This lightweight mode is independent from the quality preset, so can be enabled/disabled to find the best balance for you
        - Automatic day/night ambient lighting that adjusts based on sun position
        - Modified SEGI shaders to work properly with Stationeers rendering

        Built upon the work of
        Sonic Ether (original SEGI): https://github.com/sonicether/SEGI
        Erdroy (initial Stationeers port): https://github.com/Erdroy/Stationeers.SEGI
        and Vinus (previous implementation): https://github.com/TerameTechYT/StationeersSharp/tree/development/Source/SEGIMod

        Configuration available through F11 in-game menu, StationeersLaunchPad config, or BepInEx config files.

        Source Code: https://github.com/TheRealBeef/Beefs-Stationeers-SEGI-Plus
    </Description>

    <ChangeLog>
        1.2.4:
        - Fix glowing robots, they no longer glow wildly

        1.2.3:
        - Another pass on adaptive performance
        - Only two strategies now: Balanced and Reduce Distance first
        - Added min distance option for reduce distance first
        - Properly handle when desired framerate is set above in-game framerate limiter

        1.2.2:
        - Shrunk F11 menu slightly
        - Added color backgrounds to each section to improve understanding of grouping as it's getting crowded
        - Added Adaptive Strategy option to adjust what's prioritized in adaptive performance mode
        - Added long-term accumulator for adaptive to bump quality up slightly when framerate stays stable but slightly below target

        1.2.1:
        - Widened adaptive framerate slider choices
        - Automatically remove/mark read the major update popup if go into world
        - Added an x10 multiplier option if you want to play around with silly gain values
        - Darkened background of F11 menu slightly

        1.2.0:
        - Added first pass of adaptive framerate control that works with the quality setting to try and improve performance
        - This can be used at any quality setting and with or without lightweight mode
        - This isn't automatically enabled as it's yet experimental - you can enable this in settings

        1.1.1:
        - Improved lightweight mode cleanup
        - I inverted the new sun calc like a big dumb

        1.1.0:
        - Added more info to the F11 menu to help with understanding settings
        - Fixed F11 menu breaking when returning or used in main menu/splash screens
        - Added F11 menu scaling so it is bigger at 1440/4k
        - Better day/night transition (now transitions between 2-10 degrees sun elevation instead of +5/-5 deg)
        - Added Advanced Furnace to object exclusion list in lightweight mode
        - Thanks **BassManDan** for your feedback helping get this update done quickly

        1.0.0:
        - Updated plugin architecture
        - Added lightweight rendering with cached object culling by layer/emissiveness
        - Implemented quality preset sliders
        - Improved scene management
        - Day/Night diffuse light adjustments
        - Updated SEGI Shaders to play more nicely with stationeers
        - Improved layer culling for regular rendering
        - Updated config menu system
    </ChangeLog>

    <WorkshopHandle>3573780489</WorkshopHandle>

    <Tags>
        <Tag>Graphics</Tag>
        <Tag>Lighting</Tag>
        <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
        <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    </Tags>

    <InGameDescription>
        <![CDATA[
<size=30><color=#ffa500>Beef's SEGI Plus</color></size>
<b>WARNING:</b> <color=#ff0000>This is a StationeersLaunchPad Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed.</color>
See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

There is an in-game config menu with F11.

A modified version of SEGI (Sonic Ether Global Illumination) for Stationeers with shader fixes and performance options.

- 4 quality presets (Low/Medium/High/Extreme)
- Lightweight Mode that renders only emissive objects for maximum performance at the cost of more light leakage
> This lightweight mode is independent from the quality preset, so can be enabled/disabled to find the best balance for you
- Automatic day/night ambient lighting that adjusts based on sun position
- Modified SEGI shaders to work properly with Stationeers rendering

Built upon the work of
Sonic Ether (original SEGI): https://github.com/sonicether/SEGI
Erdroy (initial Stationeers port): https://github.com/Erdroy/Stationeers.SEGI
and Vinus (previous implementation): https://github.com/TerameTechYT/StationeersSharp/tree/development/Source/SEGIMod

Configuration available through F11 in-game menu, StationeersLaunchPad config, or BepInEx config files.

Source Code: https://github.com/TheRealBeef/Beefs-Stationeers-SEGI-Plus
]]>
    </InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>

